Chuma Achike

FULL-STACK WEB/Mobile DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

I am a passionate software developer with expertise in full-stack web development. I am drawn to solving real-life problems using software. I am good at problem-solving because I can easily identify problems and suggest solutions.

EXPERIENCE

MICROVERSE, Remote

Mentor (Volunteer), February 2022 - Present

- Mentoring over 20 junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposing improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Providing advice and tips on maintaining motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

UNN Business School, Enugu, Nigeria

Head of Information, Communication, and Technology, August 2021 - Present

- Designed and developed the new Business School Website & portal for the business school with over 100 daily visits in the website and 1,000 users on the portal. (WordPress, Moodle)
- Raised 20 million Naira for the Business School complex
- Managed a team of 5 to help maintain the ICT infrastructure of the business school

University of Nigeria, Enugu, Nigeria

Network Engineer, October 2018 - August 2021

- Managed and maintained the university's network infrastructure, school portal, and website.
- Liaised with the ISP to ensure internet connectivity was always available to the local network.
- Maintained the access points in 5 different locations in the school

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE, February 2022 - Present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours(and counting) mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed new skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

edwardachike@gmail.co m GitHub LinkedIn Twitter

SKILLS

Portfolio

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, iOS, Android Kotlin

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, Python, Java

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Leadership, Responsibility, Innovation, Active learning, Observation, JIRA

PROJECTS

Math Magicians

- Built with (React, CSS, HTML, React) Live Demo<u>Link</u>

ToDo List

- This is a simple ToDo list app.
- Built with JavaScript, CSS and HTML Link

Space Travelers

- This is a space travelers app where people can view available rockets and book trips -Built with JavaScript,

CSS and HTML, React

University of Nigeria June 2010 - June 2016

Bachelors, Engineering

- Completed courses on Python, Java, and C++.
- Took 11 courses on microprocessors and different integrated circuits (Arduino, Raspberry Pi, 555 timer, LM741).
- Built 6 computer software and 2 hardware projects.

<u>Link</u>